Front-End Developer

LEE LEMUS

Phone: (914) 826 3937 | Email: leelemus@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/leelemus Portfolio: https://leelemus.github.io/portfolio/ Address: 427 Pluto Street, Madison, WI 53718

Summary

Dynamic and resourceful Front-End web developer with experience in e-commerce, sales, and digital marketing. Is very comfortable working in a team environment. Enjoys learning and applying new technologies, tools, and methodologies. Very driven with a growth and learning mindset.

Skills

Web Development / Design HTML, CSS, JS React, TypeScript Jest, React Testing Language, Watir GitHub, Jira, Agile A11Y experience Photoshop, Illustrator, GIMP Ecommerce / CMS
Google Analytics
Google Tag Manager
Hybris
NetSuite
Amazon Seller Central
Channel Advisors

Digital Marketing / Other
Social Media Management
Email Marketing
SEO and SEM
Marketo
Salesforce
International Sales & Marketing
Spanish Language Fluency

Work Experience

FRONT-END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - Widen - Madison, WI - August 2019 - Present

- Design, implement, and debug front-end software features and components using React JS library, TypeScript, HTML, and CSS-in-JS.
- Create and edit unit tests using Jest, React Testing Language, and Web Application Testing In Ruby (Watir).
- Conduct code reviews for all front-end PRs in GitHub.
- Participate in grooming, story pointing, retros, and other sprint planning sessions with team.
- Work closely with UX team on design, accessibility (a11y), and technical feasibility of components.
- Create and maintain components in shared component library.
- Work with Product Development on prioritizing feature work.

DIGITAL GROWTH MANAGER - Bunker - Madison, WI - July 2018 - July 2019

- Integrated all analytics and marketing tools to create an end to end MarTech stack.
- Developed landing pages, emails, and automation tools.
- Optimized SEO and conversion performance of digital properties.
- Re-designed, implemented, and launched company blog.
- Created graphic and video content for marketing purposes.
- Worked with agencies to improve paid ad metrics.
- Tested and analyzed the performance of different digital ad and content channels.
- All activities above resulted in over 100% growth in traffic and conversions.

SALES AND MARKETING MANAGER - ARES Tool - Remote - December 2017 - July 2018

- Oversaw all e-commerce, digital marketing, and web development activities.
- Launched NetSuite E-commerce platform site and fully integrated to backend systems in under 30 days.

- Managed the advertising budget, maintaining a ROAS of 5:1.
- Developed brand identity and general brand style guidelines.
- Created and documented processes for order fulfillment and other e-commerce related tasks.
- Managed projects such as creating 20 product videos in one video session.
- Managed a team consisting of a photographer, an operations specialist, and a copywriter.

DIGITAL ENGAGEMENT MARKETING MANAGER - Nasco - Ft. Atkinson, WI - November 2016 - December 2017

- Managed digital engagement marketing for four different industry verticals.
- Implemented Social Media strategy, resulting in +200% growth in engagement, +40% growth in web traffic acquisition, and ROAS of 5 to 1.
- Managed e-commerce team consisting of copywriter, graphic designers, product data, and web developer.
- Managed execution of digital promotions and web merchandising.
- Assisted in transition to Bronto email service provider, helping increase open and click-through rate by +10%.
- Work with photography team to create imagery and video content.
- Conducted audits for transition to new e-commerce web platform.
- Work with the Merchandising department in identifying featured products, trends, events, and stories.
- Maintain and monitor relationships with agencies running Affiliate, PPC, and Display advertising.
- Managing budget for maximum ROI.

MARKETING & WEB MANAGER - Trek Bicycle Corporation - Waterloo, WI - July 2011 - March 2016

- Designed and implemented layouts, created content, and maintained product data for B2B e-commerce site using HTML, CSS, XML, and JS.
- Consistently maintained web traffic growth of at least 25% year over year.
- Drove B2B online sales to be 55% of total yearly sales.
- Created social media page with reach and engagement growth of over 40% year over year.
- Increased email newsletter list by 30% with click through rates of at least 15% year over year.
- Managing budget for maximum ROI.

DIGITAL MARKETING AND WEB MANAGER - Tech Alliance - New York, NY - June 2009 - May 2011

- Boosted lead quantity and quality by 100% by revamping marketing message and strategy.
- Redesigned web site using HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP for optimal SEO, AdWord, and Analytics performance.
- Created engaging and purposeful content for marketing and sales.
- Maintained great relationships and provided great customer service to clients.

WEB DESIGN & PRODUCTION ASSOCIATE - WebMD - New York, NY - September 2008 - June 2009

- Produced standards compliant HTML and XML content.
- Enforced coding, styling, grammatical, data, and graphical standards.
- Increased article submission rate by 25%.

ONLINE MARKETING MANAGER - Brickhouse Security - New York, NY - September 2007 - September 2008

Oversaw web and marketing projects to increase brand awareness and sales.

- Continually optimized performance of web and print advertising.
- Manage dynamic group of web, graphic, and marketing people.

WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Kuma Reality Games - New York, NY - March 2007 - September 2007

- Developed, designed and optimized user interface of games.
- Optimized web sites for SEO rankings.

Education

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS - DeVry Institute of Technology - New York, NY - 1999 - 2002